[Music]
I have a lot of respect for those of you
in this area that did not stand up
because they told you to.
All the people over here are like we're
participating. We're willing to give a
standing ovation to this guy that we've
never heard of before and we have no
idea if he's funny or not but you guys
are like he's going to have to earn it
for us.
And I appreciate you for that. I like
that. You guys are me. You guys are the
rest of the parents at the Christmas
concert I went to this winter.
The parents give standing ovations at
every band concert I've ever been to. Do
you do the same thing here in Utah?
Every single concert that you go to for
the children standing ovation? Well, I
know you guys don't.
Every single one. I don't think we're
doing the kids a service. I don't think
it's good for them to give them a
standing ovation every single time.
Recently, I was like girls, you got to
go practice your instruments. And they
go,
last concert, we just winged it. We got
a standing ovation. We're naturals.
I appreciate you guys. This is my first
time ever in Salt Lake City or Provo.
Or
first time in both both of those places.
Thank you for welcoming me.
Thank you.
I'm enjoying it very much. It's
beautiful. I didn't know how beautiful
it is and also I really enjoy being the
bad boy in town. I like that. I like
that a lot.
This is the first time in my life where
I've been a bad boy but
I am here.
I'm not just saying that to be funny.
I've had an experience. All right, I've
been here one day and I had an
experience. I I was walking from the
hotel to over here and there was a red
light and no cars so I walked across the
street. And there was two kids also at
the intersection. There was a boy and a
girl and the girl goes, I can't believe
he's just walking across the street.
That's the bad boy attitude I'm bringing
to this city.
[Applause]
I still look both ways but I don't wait
for any traffic signals.
I mentioned my girls already. They're my
they're my stepdaughters. I'm a stepdad.
Stepdad took over the lease on a couple
of girls a few years back.
Thank you very much. Are there other
step parents here? Any other broken
homes?
It's few.
Good. Glad you're able to come out.
Where's the where's the stepdad at?
Somebody raise your hand if you're a
stepdad. Right back there. Thank I said
raise your hand you clap. I mean you
guys.
Still appreciate it. How many step kids
do you have, sir?
One. One, great. And do you are you and
your wife going to have more do you
think? Got one on the way. Got one on
the way. Congratulations. Good for you.
Isn't that amazing?
It's amazing.
I think that's fun. I would love to have
more too. I I would love to have more
and I would probably love them more than
the old ones. Don't you think that that
would be true? I mean probably.
Of course not on purpose. Of course you
would do your best to love them exactly
the same.
And they would never even know unless
they watch this special.
I would do my best to love them exactly
the same. I'm just admitting that I'm a
human and there's a small chance that I
would love the new ones more and there's
nothing that I could do about it. And
for those of you looking at me being
judgmental right now, why don't you
pretend for a moment that you spent your
whole life wanting to have a boat. You
wanted to grow up and be a boat owner
and then one year you married someone
that had a boat and it was everything
you thought it was going to be and you
loved that boat and you helped take care
of it. And then the next year you made
your own boat using nothing but your
genitals.
Which one are you going to be more
excited about? That's all I'm trying to
say. It's not
I don't
I don't even think it makes you a bad
person. I think it's just a pride of
workmanship type thing.
And of course you love the old boat. You
love the old boat forever cuz that's the
boat that let you know that you enjoy
being the captain of a ship.
But if there was a hurricane and you
only had time to save one of your boats
from the harbor,
you know which one you would pick.
It's a lot of pressure being a step
parent. It's a lot of pressure. I love
the responsibility but it's a lot of
responsibility. I walk around with a
weight on my shoulders every day of
responsibility just knowing that I'm the
third person on an emergency contact
list.
That's terrifying.
Being one's not a big deal. Number one's
not a big deal but number three, if they
call me, that means there's been an
emergency and it's been going on for a
long time.
It's probably multiple emergencies if
they make it to my name on the list.
There's not even a line on the form for
stepdad. That's a write-in candidate on
the back of the form.
I'm third in line to be in charge of
these kids. I'm like the speaker of the
house. If it's me, some big stuff has
happened.
My girls are teenagers now. 14, 16. Got
a couple teenagers at home and they're
really embracing it. And every time I
tell people I have teenage daughters at
home, they're always like, oh, good luck
with that. It's really tough. You just
just somebody said it just now. No one
can resist from letting you know how
difficult it is. And it is difficult,
sure, but I think I'm good at it cuz I
know how to talk to teenagers. I speak
their language. Just the other day they
asked me for a ride to the mall and I
said, oh, do I have to?
And then later they're like, are you
going to take us or not? And I go, I was
GOING TO DO IT.
GOSH.
They have embraced all the teenage
stereotypes. Laziness is the biggest
one.
I'm proud of how lazy my girls are.
People tell me all the time that as a
parent you should want your kids to
achieve things that you weren't able to
achieve.
And I could have only dreamt of being
that lazy when I was their age.
We didn't have the technology available
for this level of laziness.
This is going to make me sound
ridiculous to the young people in the
audience but it took me 10 years to
watch every episode of Friends.
[Applause]
My girls knocked that out in a weekend.
We're having dinner together one night
and one of my daughters says, do we have
any ranch dressing for the salad? And I
said, yes we do. It's in the
refrigerator. And then she said,
uh.
And then ate her salad with no ranch
dressing.
Like she had to take a trip to the
Hidden Valley to get her hands
on salad dressing.
We don't live in a mansion. We live in a
home where our refrigerator is in the
room that we eat in.
She didn't even have to get up. But she
just sat there and angrily choked down a
dry salad
cuz she was too lazy to swivel to the
fridge.
And I respect that.
We
We took the kids to a corn maze last
fall. Are there Are there corn mazes in
Utah?
Yeah. Yeah, you guys have them.
Pretty pumped up about your corn mazes.
If you think the mountains are pretty,
you should see these corn mazes we got
going on.
This lift ticket's from Deer Creek and
this one is from a corn maze.
We're at the corn maze together for some
fall fun. 10 minutes into the maze, my
stepdaughter called me on my cell phone
and said, Andy, I'm lost.
Yeah, well, you are in a maze right now.
That's kind of the exact experience that
we paid for this afternoon.
Did you think that we had brought you to
a corn hallway? What did you think was
going to happen?
You're lost. That sounds like I'm
getting my money's worth right now.
How do you even think I could help you?
I'm also in this maze.
What are you near right now?
Corn. Oh, yeah.
I remember that part.
It's tricky.
I knew I couldn't help her so I tried to
motivate her. I said, listen, we're
leaving in 10 minutes no matter what.
Good luck to you.
If you don't make it, you live here in
the corn now. This is your new home.
Give my regards to Malachi. He'll be
raising you from now on.
It's going to be a strict religious
upbringing for you.
They're my step kids but as step parents
know, eventually you start to see your
kids have some of your personality
traits even though they don't look like
you and that's really fun for me and
terrible for my wife.
This happened recently. My wife had to
work at night so she prepared a dinner
and she left a note for the kids that
said, "Put it in the oven at 350 for 20
minutes.
That's all you have to do and then you
have your nice home-cooked dinner." My
wife got home from work and my kids had
ordered a pizza.
She asked them why they ordered a pizza
and they said, "It seemed like too much
work."
Fair enough. My wife was furious. She
called me. She's like, "What do I do?
How do I punish them?" And I said, "Did
they use their own money?" And she goes,
"Yeah." And I'm like, I don't I don't
know. I think they won this round. I
don't know how to punish them.
And then the situation happened again
where my wife was going to be gone
during dinner time. So, she prepared
prepared a meal and all they had to do
was put it in the oven and she said to
the kids, "Do not order pizza. If you
order pizza, you're in big trouble. You
didn't get in trouble last time cuz I
couldn't believe that you would have
done that. So, it was so far out of the
things that I would expect you kids to
do that I wasn't smart enough to punish
you in a timely manner.
But this time, you'll be in trouble, so
don't do it again." She got home from
work and my girls had ordered Chinese.
I love those kids.
[Music]
Sometimes my wife asks me to help teach
the kids things that I don't believe in.
The big one that we've been struggling
with is, "Don't talk about people behind
their back."
And I don't like that cuz it's been my
life experience that is the number one
place that you should talk about people.
I agree it's bad to talk about people
behind their back and let them find out
about it. So,
you should only talk about people behind
their back with a trustworthy person.
You guys aren't laughing a lot, but are
you really telling me you've never
talked about someone behind their back,
they never found out about it and
everyone just had a positive experience?
It came up cuz one of my girls came home
from school and she was upset cuz people
have been talking about her behind her
back. And I felt bad for her cuz she was
upset and I want to help and I have some
skills that could be helpful in the
situation. So, I said, "If you want,
I'll go to school with you and I'll
roast those girls that are talking about
you."
I'm a I'm a professional stand-up
comedian.
I could destroy a couple of 15-year-old
girls.
I'll put these girls in therapy if you
want me to. I'm on your side.
And then And then my daughter said,
"Andy, no one knows who you are."
All right, I guess the roast has already
begun.
I felt so bad for her, but at the same
time I was scared cuz she was mad that
people talked about her behind her back.
I was scared that she might one day find
out all the stuff my wife and I say
about her behind her back.
Cuz the stuff we say is worse, isn't it?
The kids at school are just making fun
of her backpack. My wife and I are
sometimes like, "Yeah, we don't we don't
know she's going to make it in life."
We don't know if she has the proper
tools.
And we want her to. I want her to have
nothing but happiness and success. But
at the same time, I watched her put a
Tupperware in the dishwasher with the
lid on it. So,
we got to talk about things when you're
not around sometimes.
They're constantly debating with us.
They think everything I say is wrong.
That's another teenage stereotype. We
had a half-hour debate on whether cold
pizza was better than hot pizza.
That's a stupid debate cuz cold pizza
wouldn't even exist if it wasn't for how
good hot pizza is.
I don't know why I participated in that
debate for a half hour. I think I was
just happy they wanted to talk to me.
I saw them eating cold pizza and I said,
"You want me to throw that in the oven?"
And they said, "No, we prefer cold
pizza."
No, you don't. You are too lazy to heat
things up. We've already established
that.
Cold pizza is fine, but no one prefers
it. No one's like, "I'll take one
pepperoni for delivery and take your
time getting over here.
I want the cheese hard by the time it
shows up."
You know what? Forget the whole order.
I'm just going to get a frozen pizza and
I'm going to lick it till it's soft
enough for me to chew cuz I'm a teenager
and I'm never wrong.
Teenagers are the size of real people
and that will mess with your head
sometimes.
I walk into the living room and I saw my
wife bending over to put a DVD into the
DVD player
and I thought, "Look at that. I think
that I'm going to give her a little
smack on the backside, let her know I'm
back there, you know? Maybe maybe even
forehand backhand if she leans into it,
you know?"
Not too hard though. No harder than No
harder than I beg her to do to me every
year on my birthday.
So, I got my hand cocked back. I'm ready
to party. And then
out of the corner of my eye, I see my
wife in the other room.
Is Is everyone following along
the horror show that almost took place
in my living room?
Thank god I saw my wife in time.
Thank god I saw her. So, I don't know
what I would have done if I would have
followed through on that smackaroo. That
would have ruined my life. That would
have ruined seven years of trust built
up between stepfather and stepdaughter.
If I did that, I think I would have to
be like,
"I told you no DVDs until you do your
homework."
We have rules in this house, young lady.
[Music]
I've been married for four years now. We
had a beautiful wedding. We did this uh
Japanese tradition in our wedding where
as a couple you fold 1,000 paper cranes.
And then if you're able to finish by
your wedding day, you're supposed to
have good luck throughout your marriage.
We did an Americanized version of the
Japanese tradition where the man folds
995 paper cranes.
And then the woman folds five
unrecognizable paper cranes.
And then for the rest of our lives,
we're just going to tell everyone that
we folded 1,000 paper cranes.
I hope that the luck the amount of luck
that we have in our marriage is
proportionate to the amount of cranes
that we folded for that afternoon.
I don't know why the ceiling is only
leaking on your half of the bed. Maybe
you should have folded more cranes.
Four years of marriage, it's good. And
the biggest fight we ever got in
happened the day we moved in together.
Here's what happened. I was unpacking my
boxes. My wife saw me and she said,
"What are you doing with those dishes?
You have those dishes when you were
living with another woman and I don't
want another woman's dishes in my home."
And I understand that point of view, but
before you decide that she's right and
I'm wrong, I'd like to remind you that
my wife has two daughters.
I don't
I don't think I'm being unreasonable
about these dishes.
I'm just trying to point out that you
didn't show up for the picnic
empty-handed. That's all I'm trying to
say.
If you want to get into specifics, I'd
like to point out how my dishes don't
kind of look like my ex-girlfriend.
[Music]
When I met them, they were much younger.
When I met them, they were just learning
how to lie for the first time.
And that's a cute age when they're just
trying out lying for the first cuz
little kids don't know how to lie. They
suck at it. They don't know about alibis
or alternative facts or anything like
that.
And it's cute to watch them grow into
the liars they will be one day as
adults.
One of them took some candy from our
kitchen one night and she ate it during
the night. And the way that we caught
her was she left candy wrappers laying
on the floor of her bedroom.
When we asked her where the candy
wrappers came from, she said, "I don't
know."
As if there was a chance
that we were going to say, "Oh, we don't
know either."
This is a real mystery we have on our
hands.
We may never know who ate those Twix
bars.
And my wife was upset. My wife said, "We
need to punish her. She just lied to us
and that's very serious." I don't think
we should. I don't think punishing her
solves anything. That's not smart
parenting. If we punish her, we have to
let her know that we figured it out
because of all the evidence that she
left behind. That doesn't teach her not
to lie. That teaches her to hide
evidence the next time that she wants to
lie.
I think we need to be smarter about
this.
Here's what I want to do. I want to tell
her that it was a monster that ate that
candy.
I'm going to say, "Well, if it wasn't
you, then it must have been that monster
that comes to our house sometimes.
Thank god the candy was there or he may
have eaten you."
Sweet dreams.
We should just started throwing Tootsie
Rolls on the floor of her room every
night just in case.
You know what I did? I stayed up every
night sneaking into her bedroom. I ate
those Tootsie Rolls
and I left the wrappers behind.
And that's smart parenting.
Got to keep these kids on their toes.
Plus, it's a good life lesson for her.
Lying is a necessary life skill. She
needs to get better at it.
And this way maybe she'd learn something
cuz the first time I said it was a
monster, maybe she thought I was telling
a lie.
But after waking up to evidence that
monsters are real for weeks in a row,
she's going to have to accept monsters
as a real world possibility.
And that is how you tell a lie, young
lady.
They're much better at lying now that
they're teenagers. Teenagers just have
confidence in everything they say.
It will mess with your mind.
One night they're getting ready for bed
and I said, "Hey, did you brush and
floss your teeth?"
One of my girls goes, "Yeah, I did." And
I said, "Well, that's weird cuz I just
watched you not do it. That's why I
brought it up in the first place."
It's my fault for phrasing it as a
question.
And then she said, "I told you I did it
and that's all you need to know."
Coming at me with an attitude. So, I
know I have to be a parent right now.
So, I said, "All right, if that's the
way you want to play it, I'm just going
to check the garbage in the bathroom for
dental floss to see if you're telling me
the truth."
Do you want to change your answer?
And she said, "I dare you to check the
garbage. You're going to feel stupid."
And this point I'm like, maybe she did
brush and floss her teeth. And I blacked
out for a minute.
I've never been that sure of myself.
Even now, I think I got khaki pants on
but if someone came up and was like,
"Nice dress." I'd be like, "Am I wearing
a dress? Oh, I really
But the one rule that I know about
parenting to be true is that if you make
a threat to the kids, if you threaten
them, you have to follow through on it
or else the kids are going to walk all
over you. So, we walked together to the
bathroom to check the garbage for dental
floss. And she's talking trash the whole
way there
about how gross it's going to be and how
dumb I'm going to feel.
We get there and I look in the garbage
and there's no dental floss. And I turn
around triumphant. Stepdad has won this
round.
My daughter's crying.
And the next thing you know, I'm giving
her a hug and apologizing.
Do you understand what she was able to
do to me?
She made me mad and then she got me to
apologize for getting mad.
She is really becoming a woman.
[Music]
I just think it'd be great if they were
bad at getting away with things forever
cuz right now it's not a big deal. We
find some candy wrappers on the floor of
the room, that's not a big deal. But a
few years from now, we could be finding
like rolling papers on the floor of the
room. Now, we have serious parenting to
do. Our kids are experimenting with
drugs and not the good ones you can get
legally over there in Colorado. They
come in the form of cookies.
And there's an ingredients list on the
back and all the ingredients are locally
sourced. All the butter in the cookies
comes from pasture-raised cows that only
ever eat grass and they're never forced
to live within the confines of a fence
and they're only impregnated during
consensual sex with bulls that they're
in love with.
You got to go to Whole Foods to get that
butter but it's worth the extra $30. You
When I was young, my friend got caught
with a cigarette and his mom and dad
made him smoke a whole pack of
cigarettes and made him never want to
smoke cigarettes again. I have a similar
idea if we find marijuana in our kids'
bedroom. My idea is my wife and I finish
it. That's my idea.
We finish it and then our their
punishment is they got to hang out with
us the whole time.
I'm not even a drug user but I'll do it
cuz I love my daughter.
They got to hang out the whole time. No,
you can't go play at your friend's
house. We're going to watch another one
of your soccer games on DVD. These
things are hilarious.
Everybody's going for the ball at the
same time. It doesn't make any sense.
You kids got to spread out. Have you
ever even seen people play soccer
before?
Mary just left the field chasing a
butterfly. Heather's digging a hole.
This is a disaster.
Who's coaching this team anyway?
What's that? It's It's your real dad?
Well, my fault then. You know, my bad.
I think the tough thing about being a
step parent is I don't have that
built-in thing that birth parents have
that make them proud of every single
thing that their child does.
I'm proud of most of the things my kids
do cuz they're super cool kids but I'm
not proud of everything. And people I
know that have babies are proud of
everything. I've had more than one
friend call me to brag about how early
their baby lifted its head up.
And to me, that's stupid to even
mention.
But more than one guy has called me and
been like, "Dude, guess what? My baby's
lifting its head up way before babies
normally lift their heads up.
We're We're probably going to have to
put her in a special school for girls
with strong necks or something like
that."
She's got chubby arms and chubby legs
but her neck is ripped, bro.
You got to cut slits on the front of all
her onesies so she doesn't rip it out
when she flexes her giant baby neck.
I'm jealous of that level of pride. I
want to have that, you know?
Here's an example of what I'm talking
about. One of my girls came home from
school and she said, "We ran the mile in
gym today. I guess my time." I said, "I
don't know. Maybe like 9 minutes." And
then she said, "16 minutes."
Well, I would not have guessed that you
ran the whole time. That's a terrible
time for a mile run.
Did something go wrong? What
Was there someone playing defense on
your mile run?
Did you have to do your mile run through
a corn maze? What happened?
We feed birds in our backyard. That's a
big part of our lives. We feed birds.
I don't know what the birds were doing
in our backyard before we started
spending $30 a month on bird seed but
it was rough times for the birds in the
Woodhall backyard.
Jangling around coffee mugs out there.
Tweet, tweet. Food for the poor.
My wife loves those birds so much. We
were on vacation one time and we were
running low on bird seed and she got
really upset and she goes, "What are we
going to do if the birds run out of food
while we're gone? What's going to happen
to the birds?"
And I was like, "Well, I guess they're
probably going to die. They're all going
to
We're going to come home to just a
backyard full of dead birds, you know?
We're going to have to rake them up and
move on with our lives.
We can let the kids play in the piles
but only for the first couple days.
[Music]
One time she came home from Whole Foods
with Whole Foods brand bird seed and it
was smokehouse barbecue flavor.
No, we are not feeding them smokehouse
barbecue flavor. I'm going to eat that.
I like sunflower seeds, too.
Does she think the birds are really in
the backyard like playing again? This is
unacceptable.
It's Labor Day weekend. You know how we
like to do.
We were going to have the robins over
for a party but if we're serving plain,
we'll look ridiculous.
My wife came into our house the other
day and she said, "There's a copperhead
snake in the backyard. You have to go
kill it."
I don't know if everyone's familiar with
copperhead snakes but they're venomous
snakes and if they bite you, you could
die.
And my wife came into our home and told
me to fight one to the death.
I've never fought a snake in my whole
life and she wants me in a death match,
my first time in the ring.
That's
That's not how you're supposed to begin
new hobbies. You're supposed to build up
to the difficult levels.
Let me fight a worm first. Learn some of
the moves.
So, I said to my wife, "I don't want to
fight this snake. Here's what I want to
do. I want to wait until it leaves."
And she said, "We can't do that. What if
it bites the kids or bites the dog?" And
I was like, "Okay, fair point. Let's
just not leave any dog treats or iPhones
near the snake and I think they will be
okay.
Unless that snake's a Wi-Fi router that
you got to unplug and plug back in, I
don't think the kids are going to mess
with that.
How about this? Let's have a barbecue.
Invite over all the neighbors we don't
like. Just let nature take its course."
And my wife rejects all my ideas. She
wants this snake dead. So, here's what
she does. She calls our neighbor. He
comes over and kills the snake.
That's not a fun moment in a man's life.
To be
standing in your own backyard watching
while another man protects your family.
That sucks.
It's had a real negative effect on my
self-esteem.
She heard something in the night and she
goes, "Oh my god, I heard something. You
got to go check." And I said, "I'm I'm
not going to go check. I'm going to give
Steve a call. This is his job from now
on."
I don't want to go check.
What if it's that snake's family back to
avenge his death?
What if we accidentally killed snake
Liam Neeson's son?
And now snake Liam Neeson is in the
other room right now just like, "I have
a very specific
set of skills."
[Music]
[Applause]
That was the first snake that was ever
in our backyard. Since then, I've killed
three of them. I'm on a real rampage.
Steve taught me how to do it. He goes,
"What you do is you take a shovel and
you chop the head off the snake, and you
completely remove the head from the
body, and you bury it in a separate
grave.
Which makes me think some weird stuff
has happened between Steve and a snake
at some point in his life
that he has to do this weird ritualistic
killing every time he takes one out.
I think it's cute he thinks I'm going to
dig two graves.
I'm just going to throw it over the
fence when I'm done with it.
It's made me a braver man, though, cuz
I'm no longer afraid of snakes, and none
of you should be afraid of snakes,
either, because humans have a lot of
advantages in a snake fight.
I would say arms are the biggest one.
Arms.
Arms are so useful in a fight.
If you don't believe me, find a guy with
no arms,
and then hit him in the face with a
shovel.
You're going to win that fight.
I don't enjoy killing snakes. It's not
in my nature to kill things. So, the
last time we had one in the backyard, I
called animal control, and I said, "You
guys got to get over here and get the
snake and take him to the forest before
my wife comes home and puts a hit out on
it."
And they go, "No problem. We'll be right
there. It costs $275."
I said, "Oh, you know what? Never mind.
Somebody just chopped his head off.
We're all set over here."
If you still want the body, it's in
Steve's yard. You can find it over
there.
We have this coffee shop by our house
that just started this new thing they do
called a toast bar. And if you're not
familiar with the concept yet, it's a
place where you can go get toast, and it
costs $8.
Just in case you've ever been at home
making toast and thought to yourself,
"This is way too much work for me."
I would like to outsource this job at a
5,000% markup.
[Music]
Toast used to just come free with
breakfast, but that's insulting to the
toast.
So, I went to the toast bar. I want to
treat myself. So, I order one slice of
toast with pumpkin butter on it. And
they said, "We're sorry, sir, but it's
11:05, and we stopped serving toast at
11:00."
Wha-
what for?
What happened in the back? Did the one
guy that owns the toaster go home for
the day?
How is it possible that you have lost
your ability to heat up bread?
Is it a union thing?
Is toast a breakfast food, and you're
unwilling to serve it in the afternoon?
I found out later that the toast bar
opens back up from 3:00 to 5:00. Who's
running this place?
I was so disappointed, but I was hungry,
so I just placed my order. I was like,
"All right. You win. I'll take one
grilled cheese, hold the cheese, put
some pumpkin butter on it."
We have
We have a dog. We have a dog.
Uh
golden retriever, beautiful dog, and we
we bought her. We didn't rescue her. Um
I know that's not the popular way to get
dogs, but it's also a way that you can
get dogs.
We wanted to do the rescue thing. We
signed up for the Golden Retriever
Rescue of North Carolina, and we got
denied. And that's
kind of humiliating.
We filled out forms. They came to our
house, and then they sent us a letter in
the mail that said, "We don't think a
dog should be living in your house."
We're like, "We have kids." And they go,
"Yeah, we're calling those people as
well."
And we were all really sad. We were all
really sad cuz we wanted a dog. We were
sad for about an hour, and then I
remembered, "Oh, yeah. If I want, I can
buy dogs."
So, I went out, and we bought a dog that
hadn't been traumatized by a family that
didn't want it.
And it's a great dog. It's the best dog
I ever owned, and I don't even have any
hard feelings towards that rescue
organization. In fact, I donated money
to them last year. I want to stay on
good terms with them just on the off
chance they were right about us, and I
need them to rescue this dog.
My wife and I are late to everything.
It's a big problem in our relationship.
It's at a point now where if we if we
have to be somewhere at 6:00, she tells
me we have to be there at 5:30 in order
to trick us into being on time.
And it never works. And the reason why
it never works is because I'm not the
problem. That's why it doesn't work.
All tricking me does is make me mad for
an extra half hour every time we're
running late for something.
We were running late for the movies. I
went to check on my wife, and she's
painting her fingernails.
And my initial response is anger, cuz
it's dark in a movie theater. No one's
even going to know what you've done. We
We could paint your face before we head
out tonight, and no one would know.
But I don't say anything. This is my
wife. It's the woman I picked of all the
women on the planet to spend my life
with.
And I'm a little concerned at how few of
you laughed at that. That was
That was meant to be a joke. That's a
ridiculous thing to say.
Picked out of all the women on the
planet?
Most of the women didn't even have a
chance to interview for the position.
Picked her out of a different group. I
picked her out of the women that live
near me
and would say yes if I asked them to
marry me.
It's a much smaller group.
It still means something to me, you
know? I love my wife. So, when I see her
painting her fingernails, keep my mouth
shut. I just accept this is the life
that I've chosen for myself.
I live a life where I never know what's
coming soon to a theater near me.
And then I like to see what color she
was painting her fingernails, and she
was painting them clear.
And then my brain exploded.
Are you even doing anything?
Cuz it looks like you're pretending to
paint your fingernails.
If you need me, I'll be in the front
yard mowing it with a bubble maker.
You let me know when you're ready. I got
so many bubbles to pop out here.
She told me she painted some clear cuz
it makes her fingernails shiny, and she
likes them to be shiny. And I support
her in that decision.
I want them to be shiny, too.
I just feel like we could have achieved
the same results by ordering popcorn at
the movie theater.
One large popcorn, extra butter, no
napkins. We got to look we're going for.
She's late to everything. One time, my
wife was late to watch Netflix in our
own home.
And that should be impossible because
Netflix starts whenever you want.
We picked out a movie,
and then she goes, "Don't start it yet.
I have to go to the bathroom."
And then about a half hour later, I'm
just sitting there by myself
wondering what's happened to my wife.
I go looking for her.
I found her in the shower.
And I said, "Why would you take a shower
when you know I'm waiting in the other
room
by myself staring at a blank screen like
a moron?"
And she said, "I'm not taking a shower.
I'm rinsing off."
And that's how my wife beats me in
arguments. She just denies that she's
doing the thing I said I was mad about,
and I don't know how to fight back
against that.
I'm not smart enough.
I have 37 years of life experience
leading me to believe that what I'm
seeing right now is called a shower. You
just told me that it wasn't. I don't
know where we go from here.
You're in a shower. You're naked.
There's water. How is this not a shower?
If you were rinsing off, you'd be in a
colander, and I'd be holding you under
the sink
like a bunch of grapes trying to get the
pesticides off.
That's how she always wins.
We were on a road trip one time, and she
fell asleep. I said, "Honey, you got to
wake up. I'm sleepy, too. I want you to
talk to me."
And she said, "I'm not asleep. I'm
resting my eyes."
[Music]
All right.
Are you also airing out your throat?
Why is your mouth been open for the last
15 miles?
You should start chewing because you
have three gummy bears in your mouth
that you don't even know about.
That's how I've been staying awake. I'm
over here shooting threes with the
yellow gummy bears, just trying to stay
alert.
I would have kept going, but I'm only
giving you the gross flavors.
You think you're going to get a red one?
You're not even awake. You're out of
your mind.
Sometimes people ask me
how what my wife thinks about being in
so many of my jokes, and maybe this will
explain it to you. Um I did some of
those jokes on Conan about her being
late to things, and hundreds of
thousands of people watched it on the
internet and liked the video and wrote
comments about how funny it was and how
they knew someone in their life that's
the same way. Other people wrote
comments about how I looked like fat
versions of celebrities, but those
aren't the ones I want to focus on.
So,
my wife
was running late for something, and I
brought up this video to her as
evidence. I said, "Hundreds of thousands
of people have laughed at this video,
almost as if in agreement with my point
of view that it's crazy that you're late
to everything. Doesn't that make you
want to change your lifestyle just a
little bit?"
And she looked at me, and she said, "Me
being late is our number one source of
income right now."
Thank you very much for coming, guys.
Good night. Thank you.
Thanks for all.
Hello. Thank you. Thank you.
Thanks so much for
I'm King Arthur now, apparently.
The king.
Thank you for being here, you guys. This
is really exciting. It is great to be
here with Ed Angel. We are going to put
those filters to work tonight.
None of my jokes are particularly dirty
or anything. I just I just like to tell
my jokes naked, so
[Laughter]
Just
Just a thing I do.
If you're watching this clean, then like
in about 10 seconds your video is just
going to cut, and I'll be like waving
goodbye and like tightening my belt
buckle and
And that'll be it.
No, I'll leave I'll leave these on.
Uh this is kind of my my look these
days.
Uh it's kind of the the look of a man
who's run out of ideas, you know?
That's That's what I would call it. It
kind of it takes you a while to kind of
find your look, you know, how you're
going to dress, how you're going to
present yourself. There's like a really
key moment. I think it usually happens
like in high school where you become
like clothing self-aware,
you know? You see a photo of yourself,
and then for the first time you're like,
"Huh.
So that's how those clothes always look
on me. Okay."
And you realize the past 16 years have
just been Old Navy draped across
your lumpy body.
And that's a big moment, you know? You
can start to build from there. That's
ground zero. It's a good moment.
Uh I've learned something about buying
clothes over the years. You know how
they say you should never buy groceries
when you're hungry?
It's the same sort of thing. You should
never buy clothes when you have high
self-esteem.
Don't ever do it.
Maybe Maybe one day a month I totally am
the guy who can wear Nike high-tops, you
know?
But the other 29 days I'm not. I'm this
guy, all right?
It's a bad investment.
I don't know. I was I was buying shorts
last summer, and it must have been like
a good self-esteem day because I tried
on the shorts and they went down to like
about here.
And I was like, "Yeah, these look like
shorts that a straight man could wear."
[Laughter]
And they weren't.
Absolutely were not.
But you don't have those thoughts when
you have high self-esteem, you know? You
need the low self-esteem to rein you in
a bit. Cuz if not, you have thoughts
like the one that I had, which was,
"Yeah, they're a bit shorter than usual,
but Daniel Craig wore short swim trunks
in Casino Royale, and no one gave him a
hard time."
And and like nothing seems wrong about
that statement. You're just like, "Yeah,
that's a good point. Ladies love Daniel
Craig. Double-oh heaven. Yes.
I'll take three pairs."
[Laughter]
And then sure enough, you try them on a
week later, and you're like, "Why are
all these tiny boats on my shorts?
I look like a body positive sailor.
I can't wear these with my high-tops."
Bad choice.
What I do, I try to imagine my high
school bully whenever I try on clothes,
and
I'm wearing the outfit, and if he leaves
me alone, I can feel good about the
outfit, you know?
[Applause]
That's the ultimate test, you know?
It's like where like self-consciousness
meets self-defense, you know?
My high school bully, his name was Tyler
Johnson.
Uh if that sounds like a made-up name,
it's cuz it totally is.
I'm afraid he's going to like track me
down and be like,
"SAW YOUR SPECIAL, ALLEN."
I'M JUST GOING TO PLAY IT SAFE. I DON'T
know what his comedy preferences are,
you know?
But uh
I don't know. I owe my whole fashion
sense to that bully, you know?
It feels weird to kind of praise a bully
like that, but I don't know. Sometimes
you're walking around the grocery store,
and you see one of those guys who has
like the cargo shorts with way too many
pockets and that like square-looking
haircut, and you're just like, "Man,
that kid did not get bullied enough."
[Music]
Yeah.
I mean, bullies do a lot of terrible
things, but they do get you out of that
phase, you know?
It's nice to get some honest feedback
once in a while.
You see, I learned from a very young age
that if I wore the free T-shirt I got
from Chili's the night before to school
the next day, Tyler Johnson was going to
twist my nipples.
Okay?
And I'm better for that. Okay?
Basically, a bully's job is to say
terrible things about you and make you
feel bad about yourself until you're old
enough to just do that naturally for
yourself.
[Applause]
Thank you. You guys just applauded
bullies. I hope you're okay with that.
Take a look in the mirror. Wow.
All right.
So I am pretty nervous uh tonight, not
going to lie. I know I seem so composed
and
in command of the situation right now.
Uh but I do get nervous, and I've come
up with like a strategy to deal with it
over the years.
Uh full disclosure, it it doesn't work.
Um
It is not a good strategy, but I'll I'll
teach you, all right?
So I'm a college student, and we'll
we'll do a practice example. Let's say
I'm about to go take a test, and I'm
nervous for the test. Here's what I do.
I get ready,
and I tell myself,
"Don't be nervous.
This test doesn't even matter."
And that would be like a great place to
stop,
uh but I tend to overcorrect.
I'm like, "Yeah, this test doesn't
matter.
Nothing matters."
[Laughter]
And I mean, I I guess it works. Like I'm
never worried about the test anymore. I
don't get out of bed the next day,
but it does work.
You get rid of one problem, but it's
only by creating a much bigger problem.
It's like you don't want to do laundry,
so you set your house on fire.
Guess it works. I don't know.
I do like the same thing if I'm nervous
before a date. I'm like, "Don't be
nervous. Love is just an illusion, and
everyone dies alone. But sure Sure,
Karen, I'll go see Zootopia with you."
Then I am cool as a cucumber the rest of
the way.
I don't know. It's probably not a
healthy way to deal with stress, you
know? Some people call it an existential
crisis, but I give myself existential
pep talks, you know?
That seems weird. I don't know what
LeBron James does to get ready for a
game, you know? I don't know what he has
in his Beats by Dre headphones, but I'm
pretty sure he's not bumping Crime and
Punishment, you know?
I am pretty sure about that. Can you
imagine that postgame interview? Like,
"Wow, LeBron, excellent performance
tonight. How did you manage to stay so
calm and so composed out there?"
"Well, Doris, just try to remember that
Raskolnikov killed a man and felt no
guilt."
[Laughter]
"Well, it certainly showed tonight,
LeBron."
I don't know what's in those Beats by
Dre headphones. Maybe that's what he
does. I don't know. We can't be sure.
I'm not nervous, though. I'm good.
Uh like I said, though, I'm a I'm a
college student right now. I'm actually
about to graduate in 3 months. YEAH.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU. COLLEGE IS A
really exciting time because, you know,
it feels like you can make your life
into whatever you want it to be. You can
be a totally different person than you
were in high school, you know? Tyler
Johnson's not twisting your nipples
anymore.
The door is wide open.
Uh,
you know,
you can follow your dreams and and do
what you're really passionate about.
Uh, which is why I chose to study
accounting for 5 years.
Yeah.
I don't know. Do you ever look at your
life
and you're just like,
"Who did this?"
[Applause]
"Who thought this would be funny?"
Oh, I did this. That's right.
So, I'm an accounting major.
Uh,
the program I'm in is really
competitive. It's a tough program. And
being in a tough business school is like
being on a sinking ship
where they have to like throw stuff
overboard so the ship stays afloat.
Except instead of throwing over excess
cargo, it's all of your likes and
interests.
So, we got to get this off the ship.
What's in there? Uh, feelings.
Don't have time for those this year.
Just going to have to do without.
Why did we ever come aboard the USS
Business?
We were so enticed by the exotic
destination of a business park in
Billings, Montana.
I don't know what one would do on the
USS Business if that were a real thing.
Like, what's the nightly entertainment?
You just get drunk and watch TED Talks?
Is that what happens?
[Laughter]
We got Ted in the house tonight, I
guess.
Just the reaction I was going for.
When I tell people I'm studying
accounting, there's I usually get the
same reaction. They just kind of like
recoil.
You know, they're like worried I'll get
it on them or something.
I'm like, "Don't worry, it's not
contagious."
It will kill you, though.
[Music]
Accounting students, we know it's not
cool to study accounting. It's fine. We
know. We try and convince ourselves
otherwise, you know? There's like not a
week that goes by without one of my
professors saying something like, "So,
as you can see, accounting actually is
pretty cool."
And just as a general rule of thumb, if
you have to remind yourself how cool
something is, it's probably not that
cool.
The only time you say stuff like that is
if you like accidentally hear a Wiggles
song or something. You're like, "Yeah,
this is pretty cool, actually. Kind of
got a disco bend to it, huh?"
You know, it's not like Bono finishes a
concert and he gets all of his friends
together and he's like, "So, as you can
see, fronting the influential Irish rock
band U2 is actually pretty cool.
Really gives me a chance to use my
creative problem-solving skills."
Add me on LinkedIn.
I'll be performing on the USS Business
next week.
Check it out.
My first day in the business school,
this is a true story.
I walked by a classroom and there was a
professor who was giving a lecture kind
of introducing his class
and he said, "Ever since I was a child,
I've always been passionate about
quality management."
Okay.
That's what we're going with. That's the
line.
Ever since you were a child. So, in
elementary school, when kids are going
around the room introducing themselves
and Timmy's like, "I LIKE COMICS." And
Becky is like, "I like ponies." You were
like, "Boom, quality management."
That's you.
If any of you kids need some some
quality manage, just hook me up, you
know? I'm a manage it. It's what I do.
As I've gone through the accounting
program, though, I've kind of felt more
and more like comedy is what I wanted to
with my life, you know? I don't want it
to be just a hobby.
And that's not like a joyous realization
that a person has, you know? It's like
when Harry Potter tries on the sorting
hat and he's just like, "Not Slytherin.
Not Slytherin." That's my attitude
towards comedy, really.
It's not
You know, like you don't tell your
parents you're planning on doing comedy
without like really preparing them
before you tell them that.
Just like, "Listen, guys, I felt this
way for a long time and this is
something I feel I've always known about
myself."
They're like, "It's fine. We saw the
shorts. We know."
[Applause]
One step ahead of you there.
No, nothing.
Um,
I don't know. Realizing that you want to
pursue a career in comedy, it's like
taking like years of self-reflection and
you wake up one day and you realize that
the only thing that will make you happy
in life is being a Cleveland Browns fan.
You know, like, you know the next couple
of years are going to be pretty rough,
you know?
It's going to be like at least 15 years
before anything good might happen to
you, you know? At the very earliest, you
know?
You don't think it's I don't know.
Comedy as a career, wouldn't wish it
upon anyone. Probably Is it as bad as
being a Browns fan? I don't know. Who's
to say? Do any of you know who Dave
Logan is? The iconic Cleveland Browns
player? No. Your team plays in
Cleveland, all right? A city whose
greatest cultural achievement is the
Drew Carey show.
All right? Your logo is a brown helmet,
all right?
You can't even put the logo on your
helmet because it would create this
infinite sequence of helmets inside of
helmets.
[Applause]
Wouldn't wish this life on my worst
enemy, you know?
But now,
uh, I tell my fellow accounting students
that I'm thinking about pursuing a
career in comedy and that gets the room
quiet really quickly.
Everyone else talks about where they're
going to work when they graduate and
they're like, "Deloitte, KPMG, Goldman."
And I'm like, "Comedy writing."
You know, they're like, "Oh, what's
what's the starting salary on that?"
Zero.
"Zero dollars?"
Yeah. Well, any currency, really.
Take your pick.
"How about you? What are you going to
study? What are you going to work in?"
Quality management.
It's a good career.
That's fair.
I'm looking for a job right now, though,
you know? Something uh, something to pay
the rent while you pursue a career being
a Cleveland Browns fan.
Uh, it's hard to find a job, though.
There's a lot of things that suck about
it, you know? The resumes, filling out
cover letters,
thinking you're dead.
Just me?
I'll explain myself.
So,
a couple summers back, I was in high
school and I'm looking for just like a
crappy summer job, you know? Something
to just hold me over.
And do you have like the jobs you want
and then you have like like the Subway
Tier, I call it.
It works on two levels because Subways
are below the ground and because the
restaurant Subway is not a place you
want to work.
Why it's called the Subway Tier. Anyway,
I like I didn't hear back from any of
these places and like after a week of
not hearing back from Pizza Pie Cafe,
there's some part of you
there's some part of you that really
wants to believe that this is all just
like a weird sixth sense thing that's
happening, you know?
You've actually been dead for a month.
I actually had a thought cross my mind
this summer when I was like, "Well,
maybe something just killed me and I
didn't notice, you know?"
Like thinking I was dead was easier for
me to accept
than the fact that Pizza Pie Cafe did
not want to interview me, even.
It's not a good feeling.
A lot of the jobs I applied for that
summer, though, uh, they have you fill
out these quizzes uh, and they always
tell you the same thing. "There are no
wrong answers."
Which why are we taking this, then?
That's
Well, look, another perfect score.
An impressive batch here, huh?
They always ask you questions, you know,
like,
"An employee or a customer pays you too
much money. Do you keep the change for
yourself or do you go give it back to
them?" And obviously they want you to
say you're going to give the money back,
right?
The weird thing, though, is one of the
quizzes I was taking,
instead of giving me like a right answer
and a wrong answer, they just gave me
two wrong answers.
There was no longer any right choice.
So, they're just like, "Do you steal
money from the register or do you blame
it on your coworker?"
I'm like, "Hold on. I don't want to do
either of those things, okay?
Surely there must be a right choice
here."
Feel like the hiring manager must have
been watching Breaking Bad or something
when
they wrote this quiz. I'm like, "All
right, the feds are hot on your tail,
all right? Do you take the money and
leave your family or do you shoot the
cop?"
I did not know there was so much moral
ambiguity to making a pizza.
"Listen up, kid. This is the real world,
okay? This is Pizza Pie Cafe.
Things ain't so black and white out
here.
Sometimes you can't tell where the
cheese stops and the pepperoni begins.
We need an employee who's not afraid to
make the hard choices and step on some
throats."
Seriously, felt like they were just
going to bring me into the interview and
like hand me a gun and there's like an
old lady tied up in there.
"Finish the job!
You said you'd do anything to get this
job. Now prove it!"
So I killed her.
Didn't get the job, though.
Not enough experience, I guess.
Experience of hiding old ladies' bodies
in pizza dough.
Oh, well. You live and learn.
So yeah, looking for a job. I did find
an apartment, though. Uh it's a really
nice place. I'm really happy with where
I'm living now. Uh
and I actually got to live there by
myself for about a month. I had a month
before my roommates moved in and just
had the place to myself. And it turns
out that you learn a lot about yourself
when you live alone
in like a very short, concentrated
amount of time.
So I learned I still totally believe in
ghosts.
Very much so.
I always thought of myself as like a
very rational person you know,
I don't just project, you know,
superstition onto things I don't
understand. Yeah, that lasted a day.
When you live alone, your life turns
into the Blair Witch Project, all right?
You see the world in grainy found
footage.
And you're always late to stuff because
anytime you need to like go downstairs
or cross a corner, it's stretched out
for like 3 minutes.
Takes way longer than it should.
I don't know.
On one hand, I totally get it. There are
no ghosts. We all know that. But when
it's like midnight in your apartment and
your pipes are creaking and you don't
understand why or you walk by your TV
and it crackles and it just goes, "6
days left!"
I don't know what that is.
We may never understand.
So yeah, ghosts are real.
I'm also I also found out I get really
paranoid when I live alone. Like every
single person I see in the street is
just waiting to rob me.
Which like believing that a burglar
wants to like
rob a 24-year-old's apartment, that's
like much more unreasonable than
believing in ghosts.
Yeah.
Like what's he going to What What
Ocean's 11 heist are they planning for
my apartment, you know?
"We hear he just got a new toaster for
Christmas.
It's got three slots in it."
They're going to take my Abbey Road
poster, you know? He's going to run off
like, "It's just so well sequenced!
Each track is so strong."
He runs off with the poster. No, all
right? But that's how I feel.
The other weird thing about where I
live, there's like lots of kids
uh in the neighborhood where I live,
which is a whole weird thing. I found
I'm actually really awkward around kids,
particularly when their parents are
around.
Because like
hear me out, all right?
Like
you want to seem nice, but not like too
nice.
Just like sometime in the last year I
rounded this corner where I'm no longer
the one in danger in stranger danger.
[Applause]
And that's a weird feeling.
Very sudden realization you have, you
know?
We've swapped positions in the van.
So now I'm always like way weird around
kids when their parents are around, you
know? Cuz it's hard to just kind of like
casually slip into a conversation that
you don't want to kidnap them, you know?
Hard to just slide it on in, you know?
So I'll be like out in the street
walking home and I'll see a kid. I'm
like, "Oh, hey, did you hear about the
new Zelda game?
Yeah, it looks really good. I totally
rather steal that than an 8-year-old
boy."
Then like the mom walks over. I'm like,
"Oh, hey." And she's like, "You want to
play catch with Timmy?" I'm like, "No,
I'm good. I'm just going to watch. No,
I'm not going to watch. Not
I don't even own binoculars."
It's a weird feeling. That's all.
So I don't know. I'm like Right now I'm
just trying to get my life in order for
after I graduate, you know? Try to find
a job, find a place to live, and you
know, I just want to make my life into
what I want it to be, which is often
times hard to do, you know?
Like I just It's easy to say stuff like,
you know, I want to be in a healthy
relationship and date people, but doing
that is like a whole different thing.
I had a bowling date last week. That's
what I'm getting at.
Yeah.
I know what you're like. Bowling, yeah,
pretty lame. I told you right up front.
This is a man who's run out of ideas,
okay?
We knew that going into this.
But what can I say? Every It happens
like once a year. You just get this urge
to and you're just like, "I MUST BOWL!"
[Laughter]
I DON'T KNOW WHERE IT COMES FROM, but
there's
there's like some primal thing to
bowling.
It just feels good, you know?
So why not make a date out of it, you
know?
I don't know if like our ancestors This
is like an evolutionary thing where our
ancestors protected themselves by like
rolling stones at
enemy tribes or something and that's why
it's so good. Can you imagine like
"Chief, a pack of wolves is approaching
us.
How many of them are there?
10, by the looks of it.
I think if we hit the center one, we can
hit all of the other wolves as well."
[Laughter]
I don't know where it comes from, all
right? I just know I like to bowl
sometimes.
So we were on this bowling date
and here's the thing with bowling dates.
There's only like this weird 5-second
window for you to interact with the
other person
after you throw the ball and there's
really not much to comment on and that
Usually it's just like whatever just
happened with the ball you threw, which
in my case is usually like, "Oh, seven.
That's kind of good, but not that good.
Ho ho ho."
And it's hard to come up with 10 frames
of that, you know?
Not easy.
Uh the girl I was on this date with,
though, she was
she was very bad at bowling.
And
there's there's like an interesting
spectrum with bowling where it's kind of
like, "Ah,
aw shucks, cute." But then you cross
like a certain point
and it just becomes like genuinely
concerning.
Because I I honestly don't know how you
live to the age of 24 while only bowling
a 24, you know?
I don't know.
Like I get on one hand, bowling is a
sport. It's fine if you're not good at
it. But on the other hand, I also feel
like it's just kind of a basic life
skill.
Yeah.
If you're pouring a glass of milk, it's
not okay if all of a sudden YOU'RE LIKE,
"WHOA!
[Music]
[Laughter]
SORRY, I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
CAN YOU SHOW ME? AM I doing this right?
How do you hold it?"
It's not okay if you're like driving a
car to just veer off into the other
lane. We're not like, "Oh, it's fine.
We'll just put up medians. We'll put up
medians."
Would that help all?
All I'm saying is if you can't bowl like
a 75 or higher consistently, maybe Earth
isn't the place for you.
And for some reason she got really upset
when I told her that.
I don't know.
I tend to get like really attached
really quickly when I date someone.
That's kind of like my go-to move.
That's my thing.
And people always say it's a bad idea.
You know, they're like, you know, only
fools rush in. Don't put all your eggs
in one basket. Which is fine, but like
where else do you want me to put my
eggs, man?
Right? Where else if not this basket?
And do I look like the guy who has like
an abundance of other baskets available
to him?
Right?
Got to put them somewhere. Have you
tried carrying around a bunch of eggs?
They just fall everywhere. You have to
put them in a basket.
Just looking for somewhere to put my
eggs.
It's actually what my Tinder bio says.
Just
[Applause]
Got to put those eggs somewhere.
Sometimes
getting attached like that gets me into
trouble.
Uh
I had There was this one time I had a
really good date with this girl, so I
got home and I was like, I'm going to
look at her Spotify profile.
It's an important step because
when I look at her Spotify I get to see
if we share the same taste in music or
if I need to start the process of
convincing myself that I like her music.
And I can do either one. I have no
preference.
Done both many times before.
But I'm going through her profile on
Spotify and I see she has an entire
Bruce Springsteen playlist and Bruce one
of my all-time favorite artists. And I
start freaking out. I'm like, she's the
one.
But then I scroll up and I notice it's
actually her dad's playlist.
That she's just following. And it's
like, oh, what do I do with those
feelings I just had?
[Laughter]
So I just love her dad? Is that
Is that what's going on here?
I don't know.
Sometimes though, it's it's always cool
to me when
you know, from a very early point in a
relationship someone knows that it's
going to work out, you know? Every once
in a while you'll like see a guy at a
wedding and he'll pull out this note and
he'll be like, I wrote this note the
very first day I met you. And he reads
it off and it's super romantic and it's
great.
But then at the same time
you also know that for like every guy
like that there's like eight other guys
who wrote that same note and then just
totally got dumped.
And he's just like, do I keep this note
now?
Like what if I guess if we could get
back together then it would be a cool
story like I almost threw this note
away.
It makes a great writing sample. Well
well written.
I don't know though. Like if what do you
do in that situation? Do you throw away
that stuff or do you just like keep it
forever with the hope that things will
work out, you know?
Is that how you become a hoarder?
Maybe hoarders are just the most
romantic people ever, you know?
The only difference is they keep those
notes forever.
You know? It's like, as soon as I met
you I never wanted to forget a single
day.
So I started collecting every single
newspaper from every day
for the last 20 years.
So romantic.
I don't know. If you get dumped I say
you keep the note. I think it's a great
souvenir. It's basically the romantic
equivalent of like one of those Super
Bowl t-shirts they make for the losing
team.
It's a great souvenir. That's all. Keep
it.
But it's weird. Sometimes you think you
know where you're at in a relationship
and it turns out you were totally wrong.
You just misread the situation.
It's happened to me before.
It's even happened in situations that
have nothing to do with dating.
So I worked as a secretary a couple
summers back for uh just this office.
And uh one of my duties as secretary was
to water plants in the office.
Yeah, and you're like, oh, that sounds
much more like a custodian than a
secretary. It was a small office. We
wore lots of different hats, all right?
And the other hat I wore was gloves, all
right?
So I watered these plants every day and
uh there were five of them. By the time
I finished four of the plants were doing
pretty well, but one of them was just so
vibrant and so green and it was my
favorite plant the whole time I worked
there.
So my last day in the office I was
talking to my boss and I was like,
whoever comes in after me
better make sure to take care of that
plant because it's my favorite. I always
gave it extra water and it's my
favorite.
And my boss looks at me and is like,
Drew, that plant is made of plastic.
I watered that plant every day for 4
months.
I was convinced it was growing.
And this is the first time I ever
witnessed like my whole dating life
flash before my eyes in the form of a
plant.
I thought we had something special.
I made that plant like three mix CDs.
I thought it was different from all the
other plants.
Which I guess it was in the sense that
it wasn't actually a plant.
Now I just feel like I can't trust
plants anymore, you know?
To this day though, I still don't
understand. Where did the water go?
There's no water there.
I didn't make it up.
What we had was real.
It's interesting to see how people
process a breakup though. You know, some
people their whole life shuts down when
a relationship ends.
You know, they're like, you don't
understand, Drew. No relationship I've
ever been in has ever worked out.
And I'm always like, well,
yeah, you know that's true of literally
every currently single person, right?
I'm like trying to sympathize with you
here.
Like yeah, you're in last, but you're
tied with like a billion other people.
I don't know what you want me to say
here.
If you've ever had a friend like this,
uh
you probably had the chance to be the
person who tries to like rehabilitate
them and like get them back out there
again.
Uh which basically just is you lying to
them a lot.
Honesty is not the thing they need, you
know?
It's just like
I don't understand. How did this happen,
Drew?
Yeah, obviously she thought she could do
better.
I think if that weren't the case she
would still be with you.
But based on how she's not with you,
that would lead me to believe that she
thought she could do better than you.
Does that make sense?
Whatever. I'm
I'm smart. I'm I'm handsome. I'm I'm
charismatic. Well, yeah, but you're not
maxed out in any of those things.
There's still room for improvement, all
right?
Uh I wish I'd been more confident around
her and been more fun.
Yeah, you totally should have.
Why didn't you think of that earlier?
That might have worked.
Whatever. I'll I'll find someone better.
Better?
I don't know cuz like if I lose to my
brother in a game of basketball, I'm not
like
I just need to play against someone
better at basketball.
You should find someone worse, you know?
[Laughter]
Play on easy mode for the
I'm not much better at processing a
breakup though, you know, I just get
like really emotional in random spots
sometimes, you know, like a grocery
store
or like watching a movie or
watching the 2016 film Central
Intelligence at your apartment, you
know.
Why could Kevin Hart and Dwayne "The
Rock" Johnson make it work but not me?
They were polar opposites.
They found a way.
Now, the weirdest place I've ever had
just like a random emotional breakdown
was at a Craig's Cuts.
Craig's Cuts is where I go to get my
haircut. If it sounds like a high-class
quality establishment, it's because it
is.
Drew, do they give haircuts below $10
there? No. It depends on what day of the
week you go, okay?
Quality stuff.
Anyway, I was at Craig's Cuts and they
were offering a scalp massage today that
I went. And uh if you've never had a
scalp massage before,
it's kind of
if you go like this.
This is a pretty good preview.
Maybe you think there's like a special
technique to it. No, it's just
just Denise going like this.
But uh I took him up on the free scalp
massage. How could you pass that up,
right?
And I'm sitting there
and Denise starts up, you know, and I'm
like, "Oh,
this is nice.
I like this.
I miss this."
And then just this crushing wave of
sadness
washes over me. Just hits me like a
wrecking ball, you know? I came in like
a scalp massage.
Any other place you have just like a
random breakdown, at least you can like
duck out of the way, you know, get some
privacy. But in Craig's Cuts, you're
like strapped into your chair,
forced to like stare in the mirror
as your face slowly changes.
Denise is like, "Everything all right?"
I'm like, "Yeah, I just got hair in my
eyes."
"I haven't started cutting your hair
yet."
That's right, cuz of the scalp massage.
And then you just go home and cry
watching Central Intelligence. That's
what happens.
We've all been there before, you know?
This feels like a key time in my life
right before I graduate, you know? I'm
about to graduate, be out there in the
real world, be an adult, and I want to
get things right, you know? I want to I
want to have the life that's right for
me,
and I want to be like a real adult.
And so,
right before this last semester started,
I kind of
took part in this like symbolic gesture
that to me was going to symbolize the
start of my adult life. I bought a
messenger bag.
That was was the day my adult life
started
when I mounted that single strap around
my shoulder.
Cuz you really can't be taken too
seriously with a backpack, you know?
Just as a rule of thumb.
But to me, this messenger bag was a huge
symbolic moment. And to be fair, other
symbolic moments I've had in my life,
there's really only one. It was when I
started parting my hair in this
direction instead of the other.
So, that's the bar I'm working with
here, you know?
It felt like a big moment to me.
And so,
uh about a month ago, I had my last
first day of class. I started my last
semester. And you know,
got my clothes all laid out, I brushed
my teeth, I shaved,
and then I put on my messenger bag and I
was ready.
And I get my laptop out and my books and
I'm going to load them up.
And none of them fit in the messenger
bag!
This is how I start my adult life?
How was I supposed to know there wasn't
a sample textbook at J. Crew for me to
shove in there?
Now I just look like the goof walking
around campus with a half-empty
messenger bag and three textbooks under
his arm. All right, look out world, here
I come!
All right, you guys, you've been an
awesome audience. That's my time. Thank
you so much.
[Music]